한니발 지난 이야기
Previously on Hannibal...
저 남자는 뭘
하고 있는거죠?
Can you tell me what that
man is doing over there?
FBI의 특별 자문가
자격으로 왔습니다
He's some kind of special
consultant for the FBI.
홉스 사건을
자네가 좀 봐주게
I asked you to get
close to the Hobbs thing.
너무 사적으로
임해서도 안돼네
I need to know you didn't get too close.
자네에게 필요한 건
암흑에서 벗어날 방법이지
What you need is a way out of dark
places when Jack sends you there.
절 암흑으로 보냈을 때
Last time he sent me into a dark place,
- 뭔가를 가져왔습니다
- 입양된 딸 말인가?
- I brought something back.
- A surrogate daughter?
아비게일 홉스가
용의자입니까?
Abigail Hobbs is a suspect?
그 아이가 이상적인
유인책이 아닌가?
She would make the
ideal bait. Wouldn't she?
잠시만요, 아빠?
Just a second. Dad?
It's for you.
전화왔어요
여보세요?
Hello?
그들이 알고있네
They know.
시간을 갖고 적당한
때를 기다리거라
Be patient. Wait for your shot.
준비 됐지?
셋, 둘, 하나
Ready? And three, two, one. Go.
너무나도 예뻤는데
She was so pretty.
지금도 다를바 없단다
She is so pretty.
사슴은 복잡한
Aren't deer supposed to be
complex emotional creatures.
감정을 가진
동물이 아니던가요?
그렇지
Yeah.
책에서는
I read they're
4살짜리 아이와
같다고 하던데요
like the equivalent of a
four-year-old human being.
그보단 더 똑똑하지
They're smarter than a four-year-old.
서로를 돌봐주고
And they care about each other.
환경을 생각하죠
They care about their environment.
발 밑에
생물들이 다칠까봐
They tread lightly through the underbrush
까치발을 하고
다닐 정도죠
because they don't want to hurt the plants.
우리와 다를바가 없구나
They're a lot like us.
모든 부분이 소중히
쓰여질 거란다
And we're gonna honor every part of her.
가죽은 아름다운 깔개로
Her hide is gonna make a beautiful rug.
다리뼈는 칼로 만들거란다
Her leg bones we can carve into knives.
허투루 쓰는 일은 없을게다
None of her is gonna go to waste.
아빠가 얘기 한데로
Just like we talked about.
흉골쪽부터 시작하거라
Start at the sternum.
날은 세우고
Keep the blade pointed up.
내장을 잘못 건드렸다간
Damage the organs,
고기로 못 쓴단다
you ruin the meat.
다 하고 나면
전 못먹을 것만 같아요
I don't know how I'm
gonna feel about eating her
after all this.
먹는게 사슴을
위하는 게다
Eating her is honoring her.
안그러면 단순한
Otherwise, it's... it's just...
살상이란다
murder.
자 그럼
Ok.
너무 서두르진 말거라
Nice and easy. Big breath.
한글자막 PEH
무단수정&배포금지
피드백 chrisbale@naver.com
버지니아주, 울프 트랩
잘 잤어요
Morning.
- 차 몰고 온지 몰랐는데
- 하이브리드 차죠
- Didn't hear you drive up.
- Hybrid.
스토킹 하기엔
안성맞춤인 차종이죠
- Great car for stalking.
- Um,
가서 옷 좀 걸치고 오죠
I'm compelled to go cover myself.
- 괜찮아요
- 그럼 가운이라도 걸치죠
- I have brothers.
- Well, I'll put a robe on just the same.
커피 마실래요?
You want a cup of coffee?
그것보다 여긴 왠일이죠?
And more immediately, why are you here?
아비게일 홉스가
의식을 회복했더군요
Yes, and Abigail Hobbs woke up.
그래서 남모르게
찾아 왔군요
Well, you know how to bury the lead.
제가 커피 한 잔
가져다 줄까요?
You want me to get you a cup of coffee?
아뇨, 겉옷을 가져오죠
No. I want to get my coat.
같이 커피 한 잔 하죠
Let's have a cup of coffee.
받을 때까지
전화할 셈인건가요?
Is he gonna keep calling?
잭이 걔를 좀 만나달래요
Jack wants you to go see her.
그쪽은 내키지 않나본데
And you don't.
별 수 있겠어요
Eventually.
잭은 아비게일의 아버지를
도왔다고 생각하고 있더군요
Jack thinks Abigail was an
accomplice to her father's crimes.
당신 둘 사이에
끼고 싶지는 않지만
I don't want to get in
the middle of you and Jack,
절 총받이로 쓴다면
도움이 될거에요
but if I can be helpful
to you as a buffer...
당신의 그런점이 좋았죠
I... I like you as a buffer.
잭을 당황하게
만드는 점도 좋았고
I also like the fact that you rattle Jack.
당신을 너무나도
아끼는 마음에
He respects you far
too much to yell at you,
no matter how much he wants to.
마음편히 화도
내질 못하잖거든요
전 그 점을 이용하죠
And I take advantage of that.
아비게일 홉스는에겐
아무도 없죠
Abigail Hobbs doesn't have anyone.
그게 당신이
될 수도 없어요
You can't be her everyone.
생각나는 대로
말하다 보면
When I said what I was
going to say in my head,
모욕적으로 들릴테니
it sounded really insulting,
so I'm going to find
another way to say it.
앞으로 조심할게요
그냥 평소대로 하세요
Say it the insulting way.
절 강아지 취급은 마세요
Dogs keep a promise a person can't.
식솔을 구하자는게 아닙니다
I'm not collecting another stray.
현장에서 아비게일이
말을 건게
The first person Abigail
talks to about what happened
다른 누구도 아닌
당신이었잖아요
can't be anyone who was
there when it happened.
렉터 박사님도 아니고요
So that means no Dr. Lecter either.
지 아빠를 죽인 사람이었죠
Yeah, much less the guy who killed dad.
아비게일에 대한
잭의 추측은 틀렸어요
Jack's wrong about Abigail.
제 방식대로 애한테
접근을 해 볼게요
Let me reach out to her in my own way.
메릴랜드, 볼티모어
포트 헤이븐 정신 병동
안녕
Hi.
난 앨레나 블룸이야
I'm Alana Bloom.
의사 선생님이신가요?
Are you a doctor?
네가 생각과는 다르게
Not medicine.
난 정신과 의사란다
I'm a psychiatrist.
뭘 전문으로 하시죠?
What do you specialize in?
굳이 꼽자면
Among other things,
가족 관계에 관한거지
family trauma.
저희 부모님께서 돌아가셨는지
간호사한테 물어도
I asked the nurses if my parents were dead,
대답을 해 주지 않아요
and they wouldn't tell me.
당신을 기다려야만 한댔어요
Said I had to wait for you.
기다리게 해서 미안하구나
I'm sorry you had to wait.
돌아가신거 저도 알아요
I know they're dead.
누가 묻어주셨죠?
Who buried them?
묻어 드리진 않았어
They haven't been buried.
그게 도리가 아닌가요?
Don't you think they should be?
네 어머니의 생전의 유언대로
화장을 해 드렸단다
Your mother was cremated per the
instructions in her living will.
저희 아빠는요?
My dad?
네 아버지의 경우는
좀 더 복잡했단다
Your father is more complicated.
제정신이 아닌 분이라서요?
Because he was crazy?
간호사 말로는
기억을 못한다고 하던데
The nurses said you didn't remember.
그 일에 대해서 말하고
싶지 않았을 뿐이에요
I remember. I just didn't
want to talk to them about it.
집을 팔고 싶어요
I want to sell the house.
이제 제 집일테니까요
I guess it's mine now.
학비에 충당하고
아파트를 얻을 생각이에요
I can use the money for
college, get an apartment.
이건 다 뭐에요?
What are all those?
갈아 입을 옷을
좀 가져왔단다
I brought you some clothes.
그럼 기분이
나아질까 해서
Thought a change might feel good.
만약 옷이 안맞는다면
I guessed your size, so
anything you don't want,
다시 교환해 올게
leave the tags on, I'll bring it back.
네가 들을만한
음악도 가지고 왔어
And I brought you some music too.
- 선생님이 듣던거요?
- 네 취향과 안맞으면
- Your music?
- If there isn't anything you like,
아이튠즈 기프트
카드 줄게
I've got a stack of iTunes gift cards.
안쓰고 모아둔게 많거든
I... I've got a stack of gift cards.
난 쓰지 못하고
모으는 성격이라서
I don't... do well redeeming gift cards.
선생님은 그런
분이신가보네요
Probably says something about you.
그런가봐
Probably does.
버지니아 주, 콴티코
행동분석팀 본부
I got seven families waiting.
부모님들이 목빠지게
기다리고 있네
다시 말하자면
No, let me rephrase:
딸들의 죽음을 알고 싶어
안달이 나 있네
Demanding that we find whatever's
left of their daughters.
아비게일 홉스만이
진실을 알고 있고
Abigail Hobbs may be the only
person who knows the truth.
지금 심문하실
순 없어요
You can't ask her right now, Jack.
불안감을 떨쳐버리지 못한다면
We have to create a
safe place for her first
입을 열려고 안할거에요
or you won't get any answers.
그 아이를 위하는
마음 잘 알겠네, 블룸 박사
I respect your sympathy for her, Dr. Bloom.
언젠간 자네도
날 이해할 날이 오겠지
I hope one day you'll
appreciate my lack of it.
아비게일 홉스가 아버지를
도왔다고 생각하세요?
You really think Abigail Hobbs
helped her father kill those girls?
그런 가능성도
배제할 수 없는 노릇이잖나
I think it's a possibility
that needs to be ruled out.
아비게일이 돕지 않았어도
범인을 알고 있을테지
If Abigail didn't help her
father, maybe she knows who did.
그 아이는
좀 어땠습니까?
How was she when you saw her?
놀라울 정도로
현실적이었죠
Surprisingly practical.
의심스러울 정도로
현실적이었나?
Suspiciously practical?
살인범이 아니여도
현실적일 순 있습니다
I would suggest you can be
practical without being a murderer.
걘 뭔가를 숨기고
있는거 같아요
I think she's hiding something.
외상에 의한 것일지도요
It may simply be her trauma.
더 심한 정신병일지도요
Yeah, it could also be more.
사람을 잘 조종하고
She has a penchant for manipulation.
얻는게 있어야지만 입을 열고
Withheld information to gain information.
감정을 절제할 줄을
She demonstrated only enough emotions
- to prove she had them.
- You beginning to appreciate my lack of sympathy?
- 아는 애죠
- 자네도 내 마음을 알겠지?
심한 정신병을 앓고
있다 하셨는데
You said it may be more
than trauma yet you question
아이의 공조 여부에
의문을 갖고 계시군요
her involvement in the
murders the father committed.
정신 상태에 관해
의문을 갖고 있어요
What I'm questioning is her state of mind.
윌 그레이엄과
대면을 시켜보세
I want Will Graham to talk to her.
잭, 그건 안돼요
Jack. Not yet.
자넨 윌 그레이엄의
정신과 전문의가 아닐세
You are not Will Graham's
psychiatrist, Dr. Bloom.
렉터 박사님이시지
Dr. Lecter is.
가렛 제이콥 홉스는
Garrett Jacob Hobbs...
미네소타 때까치로 불리며
the, uh, Minnesota shrike,
8명의 소녀들을
abducted and murdered
8개월에 걸쳐
eight girls
유괴해 살해했습니다
over an eight month period.
피해자들은 모발과
눈동자 색 뿐만아니라
Each of them had the same
hair color, same eye color,
연령, 신장과 체중도
same age, same height, same weight
딸 아비게일과 닮았었습니다
as his daughter Abigail.
9번째 피해자도
There was a ninth victim
아비게일 홉스와
상당히 닮았었지만
who also fit Abigail Hobbs's profile,
가렛 제이콥 홉스는
살해하지 않았죠
but Garrett Jacob Hobbs didn't murder her.
범인은 자신이
미네소타의 때까치가
The killer who did wanted us to know
아니라는 걸 알려주려고
했던 겁니다
he wasn't the Minnesota shrike.
더 악질인 놈이었죠
He was better than that.
지능적인 사이코패스에
가학성애자입니다
He is an intelligent
psychopath. He is a sadist.
같은 수법을 구사할
가능성이 낮습니다
He will never kill like this again.
그럼 어떻게
잡아야 할까요?
So how do we catch him?
홉스를 모방한 살인범에
대한 강의입니까?
Giving a lecture on Hobbs's copycat?
그 누구의 도움도 받을
수 있으면 받아야겠죠
Well, we need whatever good
minds we can get on this.
이 모방범은
This copycat is...
프레디 라운즈와 테틀크라임의
an avid reader of Freddie
Lounds and tattlecrime.Com.
열렬한 독자입니다
그자를 잘 알고
있는 사람입니다
He had intimate knowledge
가렛 제이콥 홉스의
살인 동기와 패턴을
of Garrett Jacob Hobbs's
murders, motives, patterns...
그대로 재현해
낼 정도로요
enough to recreate them and, arguably,
더 나아가 예술로 승화시켰죠
elevate them to art.
가렛 제이콥 홉스와 얼마나
잘 아는 사이였을까요?
How intimately did he
know Garrett Jacob Hobbs?
멀리서 흠모만 했을까요
Did he appreciate him
아니면 직접 만났던걸까요?
from afar or did he engage him?
홉스의 환심을
살 정도였던걸까요?
Did he ingratiate
himself into Hobbs's life?
홉스도 그자의 존재를
Did Hobbs know his copycat
알고 있었을까요?
as he was known?
가렛 제이콥 홉스가
아내를 살해하고
Before Garrett Jacob
Hobbs murdered his wife
딸을 살해하기
훨씬 전에
and attempted to do the
same to his daughter,
누군가의 전화를
받게 됩니다
he received an untraceable call.
제 생각에는
I believe
신원 불명의 발신자가
the as-yet unidentified caller
모방범일겁니다
was our copycat killer.
메릴랜드, 볼티모어
포트 헤이븐 정신 병동
보자하니 의사도
So you're not a doctor,
a nurse,
간호사도
정신과 전문의도 아니군요
or a psychiatrist.
난 기자란다
I'm a journalist.
너에 관한 진실을
말해주고 싶은데
I want to tell the truth. Your truth.
그런 이유로 널 속여서
Sometimes that involves some deception,
뭘 알아내려는게 아니란다
but know this: I will never lie to you.
그러려는거 같은데요
Sounds like something a liar would say.
네가 아는 걸
말해 준다면
If you tell me what you know,
I can help you fill in the blanks.
잃어버린 기억을
찾는데 도와줄게
그쪽이 먼저
아는걸 말해 보세요
How about you tell me what you know.
네 아버지는 미네소타
때까치였단다
Your dad was the Minnesota shrike.
네 어머니는
첫 희생자가 아니였어
Your mother wasn't the first
person your father killed.
그전에 8명의
소녀를 죽였지
He killed eight girls.
- 8명이 다...
- 절 닮았죠
- Eight girls that looked...
- Just like me.
맞아
Yes.
왜 때까치라고 부르는거에요?
Why do they call him the shrike?
그 종이 먹이감을
죽인 다음
It's a bird that impales its prey,
나중에 먹으려고
내장을 발라내거든
harvests the organs to eat later.
편치 않으신 분이셨어
He was very sick.
저도 그렇단 말인가요?
Does that mean I'm sick too?
그런 너에 대한
편견을 이겨내야해
You'll be fighting that perception.
지금 네 인생에 있어서
Perception is the most important thing
- 가장 중요한 때거든
- 남의 시선따윈 됐어요
- in your life right now.
- I don't care what anybody thinks.
신경 쓰는게
좋을거야, 아비게일
You'd better start caring, Abigail.
앞으로 네 남은 평생을
What you remember, what you tell everyone
꼬리표처럼 따라다닐 테니까
is going to define the rest of your life.
내가 도와줄게
Let me help you.
아빠를 어떻게 잡은거죠?
How did they catch him?
윌 그레이엄이란 남자가
A man named Will Graham.
FBI의 특별 자문가야
Works for the FBI but isn't FBI.
미치광이의 마음을
꿰뚫어 볼 수 있다는구나
He captures insane men
because he can think like them.
그들과 똑같기 때문이었지
Because he is insane.
나가주시겠습니까?
Would you excuse us, please?
전 특별요원
윌 그레이엄입니다
Special Agent Will Graham.
정식요원은 아냐
By Special Agent he
means not really an agent.
정신 감정을 통과 못했어
He didn't get past the screening process.
너무 불안정한 상태여서
Too unstable.
- 이제 나가주시죠
- 할 말이 있으면...
- I really must insist you leave the room.
- If you wanna talk...
아비게일
Abigail,
이분은 렉터 박사셔
this is Dr. Lecter.
우릴 알아보겠니?
Do you remember us?
당신은 알아보겠어요
I remember you.
우리 아빠를 죽였잖아요
You killed my dad.
계속 누워지냈으니, 아비게일
You've been in bed for days, Abigail.
산책 나가는 건 어떻겠니?
Why don't we have a walk?
네 엄마를 구하지
못해서 미안하구나
I'm sorry we couldn't save your mother.
손을 써 보기도 전에
이미 돌아가신 상태였단다
We did everything we could
but she was already gone.
알아요
I know.
아빠가 죽이는 걸 봤어요
I saw him kill her.
그때까지는 너무도
자상한 분이셨어요
He was loving right up
until the second he wasn't.
계속 미안하다며
Kept telling me he was sorry,
가만히 있으라 했죠
to just hold still.
다 끝날거라면서요
He was gonna make it all go away.
네 아버지와는 다르게
There was plenty wrong
with your father, Abigail,
너에겐 아무 이상 없단다
but there's nothing wrong with you.
자상한 분이셨다고 했는데
You say he was loving. I believe it.
네가 그렇게 만든거란다
That's what you brought out in him.
그것 뿐만이 아니에요
It's not all I brought out in him.
저도 똑같이 되겠죠?
I'm gonna be messed up.
안그런가요?
Aren't I?
악몽을 꿀까봐 걱정돼요
I'm worried about nightmares.
그건 우리가 도와주겠다
We'll help you with the nightmares.
네가 그걸 경험했다고 해서
There's no such thing as
익숙해 지는 일은 없단다
getting used to what you experienced.
걱정이 됐었단다
It bothers me a lot.
나도 악몽을 꾸곤한단다
I worry about nightmares too.
원치 않는 살인을
So killing somebody,
저질렀다고 해서
even if you have to do it,
죄책감을 느껴야해요?
it feels that bad?
절대로 용서받지
못 할 행동이거든
It's the ugliest thing in the world.
집에 가고 싶어요
I wanna go home.
그레이엄 특별요원님
Special Agent Graham.
정식으로 인사를 드리는게
이번이 처음이네요
I never formally introduced myself.
전 프레디 라운즈라고 해요
I'm Freddie Lounds.
지금 이걸 농담이라고
하는 말이십니까?
Are you trying to salvage this
joke from the mouth of madness?
아까는 죄송했어요
Please. Let me apologize
for my behavior in there.
제 잘못된 행동에
It was sloppy and misguided
- 마음 상하셨겠죠
- 라운즈 양
- and hurtful.
- Miss Lounds.
그만 하시지요
Now is not the time.
우리 둘 다 아비게일
홉스를 생각하는
Look, you and I may have our
own reasons for being here,
마음에 이곳을
방문한 거 같은데요
but I also think we both
genuinely care about what happens
to Abigail Hobbs.
저보고 제정신이
아니라고 하셨잖습니까
You told her I was insane.
그 말 취소할게요
I can undo that.
아비게일의 아버지를 죽인
살인범으로 모는것도 모잘라
You help Abigail see me as
more than her father's killer
홈페이지 방문자 수도
올려드려야 합니까?
and I help you
with online ad sales?
I can undo what I said.
제가 한 말은
취소해 드릴게요
상황을 더 악화시킬
수도 있어요
I can also make it a lot worse.
라운즈 양
Miss Lounds...
살인자들을 꿰뚫어
보는걸 직업으로 삼는
It's not very smart to piss off a guy
제 화를 돋구는 건
바보같은 행동이십니다
who thinks about killing
people for a living.
"살인자들을 꿰뚫어
보는걸 직업으로 삼는"
"It isn't very smart to piss off a guy
"제 화를 돋구는 건
바보같은 행동이십니다"
who thinks about killing
people for a living."
뭐가 또 바보같은
행동인지 아십니까?
You know what else isn't very smart?
거기 같이 계셨으면서
You were there with him.
나서서 말리지
않으셨던 겁니다
And you let those words
come out of his mouth.
윌도 생각없이 말하진
않았을 겁니다
I trust Will to speak for himself.
그래도 말리셨어야죠
Evidently you shouldn't.
아비게일 홉스에 관한게
아니라서 다행이에요
I'm just happy the story
wasn't about Abigail Hobbs.
그것 참 다행이군
Well, then it's a victory.
아비게일 홉스가
집에 간다고 하면
So, Abigail Hobbs wants to go home.
집으로 데려다
주도록 하지
Let's take her home.
아비게일에게 지금
필요한 건 그게 아니에요
What Abigail wants and what
she needs are different things.
통제된 환경에서 벗어나면
애한테도 좋지 않아요
Taking her out of a controlled
environment would be reckless.
현실적이라 했잖나
You said she was practical.
해리장애일 수도
있다는 건데요
That could just mean she
has a dissociative disorder.
집으로 데려다 준다면
걔도 모르는 사이에
You take her home, she may
experience intense emotions,
떠올리고 싶지 않은
그 순간을 떠올려
respond aggressively,
or re-enact some aspect
심각한 감정변화를
겪게 될 거에요
of the traumatic event
without even realizing it.
어떻게 생각하십니까?
Where do you weigh in on this, doctor?
블룸 박사의
말이 옳습니다만
Dr. Bloom is right.
그 당시의 상황을
But there is a scenario where revisiting
the trauma event could help Abigail heal
아비게일이 다시
겪게 된다면
치유됨과 동시에
받아들이게 될 겁니다
and actually prevent denial.
두분의 의견이
상충되는 거 같으니
Then we have a difference of opinion.
Therefore, I am going to choose
이분의 의견을 따르겠네
the opinion
내 계획과도 잘 들어맞고
that best serves my agenda.
자네가 말한
I need to know
모방범에 대해서도
알아보게, 윌
if you're right about the copycat, Will.
걔가 집에 간다면 어떻게
반응할 지도 모르는데요
We have no way of knowing what's
waiting for her when she goes home.
절 다시 만나주셔서 감사해요
Thanks again for meeting with me.
그러기가 쉽지 않으셨겠죠
I know this hasn't been easy for you.
그쪽이 어떻게 알고요?
Oh yeah? How would you know?
가렛 제이콥 홉스에 관한
기사를 쓰면서
I've been writing about
Garrettt Jacob Hobbs.
피해자의 가족들과도
이야기를 나눠봤거든요
I've spoken to the relatives
of some of his other victims.
홉스는 죽었어요
Hobbs is dead.
그래도 제 분은
풀리지 않았죠
He deserved a lot worse.
Him and his whole family.
정의가 실현됐다는 데
그나마 위로가 되셨겠죠
There must be some small comfort
knowing that justice was served.
위로라고요?
Comfort?
제 동생은 수사슴
뿔에 찔려서
My sister was impaled
on a severed stag head,
죽은채 발견됐죠
cut down the middle.
산 상태에서
폐를 꺼냈다고요
He pulled out her lungs
while she was still breathing.
그런데 위안이 됐을리가요
- There's no comfort in that.
- I'm sorry. I am.
죄송합니다
행복했었던 동생의
모습을 떠올려 보세요
But you have to try not
to remember her that way.
저한테 원하는게 뭐죠?
What do you want from me?
아비게일 홉스가
의식을 찾았다는 걸
I just thought you
should know Abigail Hobbs
알려드리고 싶었어요
came out of her coma.
미네소타 주, 블루밍턴
홉스 가의 자택
식인종들
여기서 엄마가 돌아가셨죠?
This is where my mom died.
그렇단다
돌아가신 곳을 표시해
뒀을 줄 알았어요
I was sort of expecting a body outline in
chalk or tape.
그런 경우는
피해자가 생존해서
They only do that if you're still alive
병원으로 후송되기 전에
그려놓는 거란다
and taken to the hospital before
they finish the crime scene.
안녕히 계세요, 엄마
Goodbye, mom.
나가고 싶다면
If you ever wanna go,
우리한테 말만 하면 된단다
you just have to say so and we'll go.
어디로요?
Go where?
병원으로요?
The hospital?
지금으로썬 그렇단다
For now.
사진을 뒤집어 놨네요
They turned all the pictures around.
범죄 현장을
정리하느라 그랬을거야
Crime scene cleaners will do that.
깨끗이도 치워놨네요
They did a really good job.
제가 흘린 핀가요?
Is that where all my blood was?
그렇단다
Yes.
자주 있는 일이에요?
You do this a lot?
현장으로 가서
살인범이 돼 보는거요?
Go places and think about killing?
그렇단다
Too often.
우리 아빠가 돼 보셨군요
So you pretended to be my dad.
그리고
And...
네 아빠 뿐만이 아니었지
people like your dad.
기분이 어때요?
What did it feel like?
아빠가 되는게요?
To be him?
그 기분은 마치
It feels... like...
네 아빠의 그림자와
말하는 것 같았어
I'm talking to his
shadow suspended on dust.
그러니까 악몽을 꾸죠
No wonder you have nightmares.
넌 네 어머니와는 다른
방법을 썼었단다
The attacks on you and
your mother were different.
절박한 상태였었단다
They were desperate.
네 아빠는 시간이
촉박한 걸 알았었지
Your dad knew he was out of time.
우리가 들어닥칠거란
경고를 받았었어
Somebody told him we were coming.
그 전화한 남자가요?
The man on the phone?
It was a blocked call. Did
you recognize his voice?
누가 전화를 했었는지
짐작 할 수 있겠니?
처음 듣는 목소리였어요
I had never heard it before.
네 아버지를 알고 있을
만한 사람은 있니?
Was there anybody new
in your father's life?
너와 안면이 있는데다
상황을 아는 사람은?
Someone you met or someone he talked about?
아비게일, 또 다른 살인범의
Abigail, he may have been contacted
소행일지도 몰른단다
by another killer.
모방범이 말야
A copycat.
또 누군가 살인을
저지르고 있다는 건가요?
Someone who's still out there?
그렇단다
Yeah.
정신나간 사람을
잡을 수 있으세요?
Can you catch somebody's crazy?
감응정신병이란거야
Folie ?deux.
네?
What?
프랑스어란다
It's a French psychiatric term.
광기의 전이를 뜻하지
Madness shared by two.
혼자선 망상에
빠질 수 없단다
One cannot be delusional
당사자의
믿음에 대해서
if the belief in question
is accepted as ordinary
공동체가 불신을
갖고 있다면 말이다
by others in that person's
culture or subculture.
가족들도 말이다
Or family.
저희 아무렇지도
않아 보였어요
My dad didn't seem delusional.
완벽주의자셨죠
He was a perfectionist.
네 아빠는 증거도
거의 안남기셨지
Your dad left hardly any evidence.
그래서 절 집으로
데리고 온건가요?
Is that why you let me come home?
증거를 찾으려고요?
To find evidence?
그것도 고려는 해 봤었단다
It was one of many considerations.
그 당시 상황을
재현해 보실건가요?
Are we gonna re-enact the crime?
두 분은
부모님 역할이고
You be my dad, you be my mom,
아저씨는 전화 건
남자인거에요
and you be the man on the phone.
널 집으로 데려온 이유는
Abigail, we wanted you to come home
잊고 떠날 수 있게
도와주려고였어
to help you leave home behind.
죽은 애들을
못 찾으실 거에요
You're not gonna find any
of those girls, you know.
What makes you say that?
왜 그런말을 하는거지?
신체의 모든 부분을
소중히 하셨어요
He would honor every part of them.
아빠는 가끔씩
He used to make
사슴의 뼈를 배관을
수리하는데 쓰셨죠
plumbing putty out of elk's bones.
그 여자애들 뼈도
Whatever bones are left
파이프를 수리하는데
쓰였을 거에요
of those girls are probably
holding pipes together.
그걸 어디서 만든거니?
Where did he make this putty?
오두막 집에서요
At the cabin.
내일 모셔다 드릴게요
I can show you tomorrow.
아비게일, 누가 왔구나
Abigail, there's someone here.
나야, 아비게일
Hey, Abigail.
다친데 아파?
So, uh, does that hurt?
가끔 아파
Sometimes.
이 주변이 뉴스에 나왔어
Everybody on the block was on the news.
학교에도 왔었어
And everyone at school.
갈보년들
Such whores.
- 인터뷰 했어?
- 아니
- Did you talk to the news?
- No.
정말이야
No!
우리 엄마가 그러지
말라고 했었어
My mom doesn't want me talking
to you, much less the news.
원래 엄마 말을
그렇게 잘 들었니?
Since when do you listen to her?
안듣는거 같아
Well, clearly I don't.
너랑 말하지 말라고
했는데 말야
I'm talking to you right now.
다들 네가 한 짓이라고
생각하고 있어
Everybody thinks you did it, you know?
너도 그렇게 생각해?
So you think I did it?
넌 그럴 애가
아닌거 같아
I don't think you're the type.
그리고 네 아버지께서도
Then again, I didn't think your father
그러실 분이
아니라고 생각해
was the murder-suicide type.
근데 사냥에 실마리가
있을거라고 생각해
Although I guess the hunting
could have been a clue.
날 말하는거야?
Mine or his?
둘 다 말야
Both, now that you mention it.
넌 아닌거 같아
I don't think you did it.
글쎄다
I do.
이곳은 개인 사유지에요
This is private property.
너가 미끼였지?
You were the bait, right?
그런 식으로
행동했었던거지?
That's how it worked?
네가 아빠의 저녁상으로
유인을 한거지?
You lure them back to daddy for dinner?
내 동생은
어떻게 꼬득인거야?
How'd you trap my sister?
- 말 걸었구나?
- 꺼져
- Did you chat her up?
- Hey! Piss off!
네 년의 꼰대가
아직도 숨이 붙어있는
Did you help your old man
cut out my sister's lungs
내 동생의 폐를
꺼내는데 도왔잖아
while she was still using...
피해자의 오빠라고 했어요
He said he was somebody's brother.
마리사, 집에 가자
Marissa! Come home.
- 싫어요
- 집으로 가자니까
- No...
- Come home!
절 좀 그냥
내버려 두실래요?
Can you stop being such a bitch?
또 보자
See you later.
잘가
Bye.
가버렸더구나
He's gone.
처음보는 사람이었니?
You've never seen him before?
네
No.
내일 오두막 집에도
가 봐야 하니까
어서 호텔로
돌아가자꾸나
We should report this, yes?
보고를 해야겠지?
네
Yes.
미안해, 알겠지?
I'm sorry, okay?
다 끝날거야
This will all stop.
내가 다 끝내줄게
Please. I'm gonna make it all go away.
싹 정리를 하셨어요
He cleaned everything.
더러워지는게
싫다고 하셨는데
He said he was afraid of germs,
잡히는게 싫어서
그러셨던거 같네요
but I guess he was just
afraid of getting caught.
네 아버지와 함께
여길 온 건
No one else ever came here with your dad...
너밖에 없단다
except you.
혼자서 모든지
다 만드셨어요
He made everything by himself.
접착제나 버터를요
Glue, butter...
모피는 이베이나
이 근처에 팔곤 하셨죠
he sold the pelts on eBay or in town.
베개도 만드셨죠
He'd make pillows.
허투루 쓰는
법이 없으셨어요
No parts went to waste.
살상을 막으시려고요
Otherwise it was murder.
저희들에게도 먹였군요?
He was feeding them to us.
안그런가요?
Wasn't he?
그랬을게다
It's very likely.
제 목을 베기 전에
Before he cut my throat,
아빠는 절 대신해서
he told me he killed those girls
so he wouldn't have to kill me.
그 여자 애들을
죽인거라 하셨어요
네 아버지가 한
행동에 대해서
You're not responsible for
anything your father did, Abigail.
넌 아무런 책임이
없단다, 아비게일
If he would've just killed me,
아빠가 절 죽였다면
그 여자 애들은 살아있겠죠
none of those other girls would be dead.
그건 모를 일이란다
긴급대응팀을 홉스 가의
오두막으로 파견하라
I need ERT at the Hobbs cabin.
아비게일
Abigail...
마리사!
그 남자와는 아는
사이라고 생각하십니까?
Do you think she knew the
guy down by the stream?
피해자의 오빠라고 했잖나
Somebody's brother.
특정 피해자였습니다
Not somebody.
아비게일 말로는
Abigail said he asked if she helped her dad
산 채로 동생의 폐를
꺼내는데 도왔냐고 했었죠
take his sister's lungs
while she was alive.
수사슴 뿔에 찔린
젊은 여성말이군
The young woman on the stag head.
캐시 보일에게는
Cassie Boyle.
니콜라스란 오빠가 있었죠
Had a brother, Nicholas.
하지만 가렛
제이콥 홉스는
But Garrett Jacob Hobbs didn't kill
캐시 보일을
죽이지 않았었고요
Cassie Boyle.
나도 아네
I know.
가렛 제이콥 홉스였다면
사체를 소중히 했겠지
Garrett Jacob Hobbs would've
honored every part of her.
아비게일 홉스를
You brought Abigail Hobbs
미네소타 주까지
데려온 이유가
back to Minnesota to find
out if she was involved
공범인지 알아보려고
그랬던 거였군
in her father's murders
and another girl dies.
이빨에 그자의 흔적이
남아 있군요
Yep, scraped his knuckle on her teeth.
보자하니 외부 조직과
There's foreign tissue and what could be
피도 남아있는데요
trace amounts of blood.
이 모방범은 지능적인
사이코패스라 했잖나
You said that this copycat was
an intelligent psychopath, Will.
어떠한 단서와 패턴도
That there would be no traceable motive,
남기지 않는다고 말일세
no pattern.
같은 수법을 구사할
가능성이 낮다고
He wouldn't kill again this way.
했잖나
You said it.
제가 틀렸을지도 모릅니다
I may have been wrong about that.
가렛 제이콥 홉스는
피해자를 때리지 않았는데
Yes, because Garrett Jacob
Hobbs never struck his victims.
이번 수법과 판이하잖나?
Why would the copycat do it?
도발을 당해섭니다
I think he was provoked.
니콜라스 보일이
Nicholas Boyle
이 소녀와 자신의
동생도 살해를 한겁니다
murdered this girl and his own sister.
- 아비게일 홉스와 공모하고서?
- 아닙니다
- With or without Abigail Hobbs?
- Without.
아비게일 홉스가
Well, do you think that Abigail Hobbs
니콜라스나 캐시 보일과
아는 사이라 보나?
knew Nicholas or Cassie Boyle?
아뇨
No...
모르는 사이라고
생각하는 건가
You don't think she knew them...
아니면 모르는 사이라고
생각하고 싶은건가?
or don't wanna think that she knew them?
모른다고 했었습니다
She said she didn't know them.
블룸 박사가 아비게일이
Dr. Bloom says that Abigail
사람을 조종하는데
has a penchant for, uh,
능숙하다고 하지
않았었나, 윌?
manipulation. Is she
manipulating you, Will?
크로포드 요원님
Agent Crawford.
모방 범죄 사실에
관해서도 틀렸잖습니까
Look, he said he was wrong
about the copycat killer.
I want to know what else he's wrong about.
틀린게 더 있을겁니다
이 두 사건은 동일범에
의한 소행이라는게
Whoever killed the girl on
the field killed this girl,
맞지 않았습니까
I'm right about that.
사체를 고정시키는 방법도
정확히 알고 있었고
He knew exactly how to mount the body.
상처난 부위도 캐시
보일과 상당히 유사합니다
Wound patterns are almost
identical to Cassie Boyle.
살인의 의도 또한
Same design, the same...
수치심 유발이었죠
humiliation.
아비게일 홉스는
살인범이 아니나
Abigail Hobbs is not a killer.
살인범의 표적이
될 수 있습니다
But she could be the target of one.
아비게일 홉스가 이곳을
영영 떠날 때겠군
I think it's time that Abigail
Hobbs left home permanently.
박사님께서 아비게일의
Doctor, would you be good
enough to collect Abigail
소지품을 모조리 챙겨서
and all of her belongings
미네소타 주에서 데리고
나가 주시겠습니까?
and escort her out of Minnesota, please?
자네는 여기에
남아 있게
Not you, Will. I want you here.
아비게일! 아비게일!
Abigail! Abigail!
너가 내 딸을 죽였어
You killed my daughter!
- 아비게일!
- 왜 돌아 온거야?
- Abigail...
- Why come back here?
왜 돌아 온거냐고?
Why did you come back here?
왜 온거야?
Why come back?
여기 있거라
Stay here.
아비게일
Abigail.
라운즈 양
Miss Lounds.
여긴 당신이 있을
곳이 아닙니다
You're on the wrong
side of the police line.
I've been covering the Minnesota
shrike long before you got involved.
미네소타 때까치를
전 부터 조사해 왔었어
널 돕고 싶어
I wanna help you tell your story.
내 도움이 절실할거야
You need me now more than ever.
- 이야길 나눠보고 싶어요
- 안돼, 안으로 들어가
- I wanna talk to her.
- No you don't. Go inside.
I'm not the only one lurking about
the Hobbs house peeking in windows.
이곳을 저만
기웃거리는 건 아닐테니까
좀 더 신경을 써서
감시를 해 주세요
You really should monitor those
police lines more carefully.
연갈색 머리를 한
20대 중반의
Have you seen a young man, mid-20s,
남자를 본 적이 있으십니까?
ginger hair? Unwashed.
그걸 물어보신
이유가 뭔지
I'll tell you if I saw him
말씀해주시면
알려드리죠
if you tell me why it's important.
허투로 쓰여선 안쨈幷
None of her is gonna go to waste.
널 해치진 않을거야
내 말만 좀 들어줘
I just want you to listen to me.
걘 내가 죽인게 아니야
I didn't kill that girl, okay?
내가 죽인게 아니라고
I didn't kill her!
기다려
Wait!
들어봐, 내가 안...
Listen! I didn't...
아비게일?
Abigail?
괜찮을게다
She'll be all right.
아비게일?
Abigail?
무슨 일이 있었던거냐
Show me what happened.
절 죽이려고 했었어요
He was gonna kill me.
그래?
정당 방위가 될 수 없단다
This isn't self-defense, Abigail.
잔혹하게 살해한거지
You butchered him.
아니에요
I didn't...
이걸 그들이 본다면
They will see what you did
네 아버지의 공범이라고
몰아가려고 할 게다
and they'll see you
as an accessory to the
crimes of your father.
아니에요
I wasn't.
네가 원한다면
I can help you,
도와주겠다
if you ask me to.
자칫하면 내가 위험해
질 수도 있겠지만
At great risk to my career and my life.
네 선택에 달려있단다
You have a choice.
네가 잔혹하게
살인을 한게
You can tell them you
were defending yourself
정당 방위라고 하던가
when you gutted this man...
아니면 사체를 같이
숨기던가 말이다
Or we can hide the body.
기억이 전혀 나질 않아요
No I don't remember anything.
눈에 초점이 흐려지다가
Maybe a blur out of the
corner of my eye and...
의식을 잃었거든요
and then a big fat cut to black.
니콜라스 보일이
아비게일과 너와
Well, Nicholas Boyle attacked Abigail, you.
렉터 박사를
뒤에서 가격했던거야
Struck Dr. Lecter in the back of the head.
- 아비게일은 어디에 있죠?
- 렉터 박사가 호텔로 데려갔어
- Well, where's Abigail?
- Lecter took her back to the hotel.
도망가던 니콜라스 보일에
상처를 냈더군
She scratched Nicholas Boyle
on his way out the back door.
마리사 슈어의 입에서
나온 조직과 피가
The blood on her hands matches
the tissue that we pulled
그것과 일치했다는데
from Marissa Schurr's mouth.
그럼 니콜라스는
도망을 간거에요?
And then what, he... he got away?
어떻게 해서든
꼭 잡아들일걸세
We'll catch him one way or another.
자넨 어디 가는건가?
Where you going?
집에 가려고요
I wanna go home.
잘 지냈니, 아비게일
Hello, Abigail.
저란걸 어떻게 아셨죠?
- How did you know it was me?
- Hospital called.
병원에서 연락이 왔단다
그 위에 있었구나
You climbed over the wall.
어디로 갈거니?
Where else were you to go?
네 집으로
돌아가선 안쨈幷
Home's no longer an option.
내려오거라
Come down from there.
자러 가고 싶지는 않아요
I don't want to go to sleep.
꿈을 안 꿀순 없단다
You can't anticipate your dreams.
꿈은 억제할 수도 없지
Can't block them, can't repress.
그 남자의 사체를
그냥 버렸어요
I didn't honor any part of him
그럼 살상이나 마찬가지죠?
so it's just murder, isn't it?
정당방위였냐며
의견이 분분하겠지
Most would argue self-defense.
그렇다면 왜 사실대로
말하지 않는거죠?
Then why not tell the truth?
의견이 분분할테니까
Most would argue.
네 아버지를 닮아서 살인을
저지르고 있다고 말이지
There would still be those who would
say you were taking after your father.
제가 죽여서 기쁘시군요
You're glad I killed him.
그 방법 밖에는 없었잖니?
What would be the alternative?
- 널 죽이기라도 했으면?
- 반대였을지도 모르죠
- That he killed you?
- I don't know if he was going to.
네 말이 맞다
No, you don't.
당신이 전화했었군요
You're the one who called the house.
그 일이 있기전에 말이죠
You talked to my dad before...
뭐라고 했던거에요?
what did you say to him?
별말 안했단다
A simple conversation,
상담을 위해서 집에
있는지 확인차 전화했지
ascertaining if he was
home for an interview.
너한테 왜 거짓말을 하겠니?
Then why not tell the truth?
연쇄 살인범인 줄 알았어요
I think you called the
house as a serial killer.
저희 아빠처럼요
Just like my dad.
네 아버지와
전혀 다르단다
I'm nothing like your dad.
실수를 저질러
I made a mistake.
쉽사리 오해를 사지
너처럼 말이다
Something easily misconstrued.
Not unlike yourself.
네 비밀은 지켜주겠다
I'll keep your secret.
저도 비밀을 지켜드릴게요
And I'll keep yours.
평범하게 내 앞에
나타나거라, 아비게일
No more climbing walls, Abigail.